<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on PHYSCI 70: Digital Fabrication</title>
    <link>http://seansullivan.ai/physci-70/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on PHYSCI 70: Digital Fabrication</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 22:39:31 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://seansullivan.ai/physci-70/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3</title>
      <link>http://seansullivan.ai/physci-70/post/week3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 22:39:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seansullivan.ai/physci-70/post/week3/</guid>
      <description>This week I built a drawing machine. I was initially inspired by spirographs that I used to have as a kid and wanted to make an automated, mechanical form of these. After exploring Pinterest spirographs to see if there were particularly interesting patterns I could create, I found this drawing machine that costs $675!! The pattern combinations were very complex and customizable so I set out to make something similar at a much lower price point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2</title>
      <link>http://seansullivan.ai/physci-70/post/week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 22:39:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seansullivan.ai/physci-70/post/week2/</guid>
      <description>My second week was hectic &amp;ndash; not only was I traveling for the weekend, my phone broke Thursday night, making documentation very difficult. This week were assigned to make a press fit construction kit. I had several ideas of things I wanted to make including:
 An Eiffel Tower A plant/flower of some sort Something Valentine&amp;rsquo;s day related A flexible self-intersecting single-piece kit Animal bookshelf (inspired by this) Bitmap art for my wall Bookends for my bookshelf A geodesic dome  My strongest interest was in the geodesic domes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1</title>
      <link>http://seansullivan.ai/physci-70/post/week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 22:39:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seansullivan.ai/physci-70/post/week1/</guid>
      <description>For the first week of class, we experimented with microcontrollers, building our first circuits on breadboards. Loosely following a guide introducing basic electronics, I built a circuit using the Adafruit ItsyBitsy M4 controller. The circuit I set out to build can be represented in the following diagram:
For power source (5V) and ground (GND), I used the 3V and GND terminals of the microcontroller respectively. After fun stripping and cutting wires, I assembled the circuit as below:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>